ERICK MENEZES SILVA

erickmenezes25@hotmail.com

+55 21 97346-6647



Full Stack Developer

São João de Meriti, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.



ABOUT ME

I have 2 years of experience in the IT Field, especially in web development and I am currently a Full Stack developer, but focused on Front-End. I'm passionate about technology and I'm always looking to learn more to specialize in the area. I consider myself a hardworking person, willing to solve problems and not afraid of challenges. I'm looking for an opportunity to join as a Front-End Developer, developing myself as a professional and at the same time contributing to the company's growth.

WORK EXPERIENCE



Linux Solutions - TI Support (Internship)

February 2020 - September 2021 / Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Remote).

Implementation, maintenance and technical support for Linux solutions. Services performed remotely, via SSH or remote desktop tools.. Work with web development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript for modifications in Moodle systems (open-source teaching platform). Task automation in linux terminal using Bash Script/Python. Code versioning with Git.



Voltalia - Full Stack Developer (Internship)

October 2021 - Current / Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Hybrid).

Maintenance and development of web applications for global use in React/Next.js, in the field of renewable natural resources. Creation of automations in Python for internal use of the company. Managing a SQL Server database and developing RESTful APIs using AdonisJS (Typescript), Django (Python) and Spring Boot (Java). Using Git for code versioning.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS



Universidade Estácio de Sá - Computer Science (Bachelor)

February 2020 - Current / Duration: 4 years / Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (In-person). Course with general subjects related to information technology (IT).



Cisco Networking Academy - Cybersecurity Essentials

Completed in May 2020 / On-line.

Course that teaches the basics of cybersecurity.



Colégio Flama - Computing Certificate

Completed in August 2018 / Nova Iguaçu, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (In-person).

Course with subjects related to Web Design, Web Development, Project Management, among others.

LANGUAGES

	Basic	Intermediate	Advanced	Fluent/Native
English	O	•	0	0
Portuguese	•	•	•	•

SKILLS

Development

HTML • CSS • Javascript • Typescript • Node.js • React • Next.js • Python • Git

Others

Agile methodologies • API development • Prototypes and wireframes designs